（薙切(なきり)えりなの寝息）
Well, sorry to spring this on you,
（幸平城一郎(ゆきひらじょういちろう)）早速で悪(わり)いが―
お前がどれだけ成長したか―
but I need you to show me
how much you've grown...
or how much you haven't.
あるいは成長してないのか―
Let's have our first cooking
contest in a long time...
今 ここで見せてくれ
久方ぶりに料理勝負と
いこうじゃねえか？
創真よ
Souma.
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）ハッ…
The Demon
I was wondering why you'd
showed up out of the blue.
唐突に帰ってきたかと思ったら
それかよ 親父
That's what you're here for, old man?
（城一郎）どうした？
やんのか？ やんねえのかい？
Well? Are you in, or are you out?
As if you needed to ask!
やるに決まってんだろ！
The Chef Who's Crossed a Thousand Leagues
The Previous Night
Who would've guessed that Souma-kun
（一色慧(いっしきさとし)）
まさか 創真君が
元十傑(じゅっけつ)のご子息とは
was the son of a former Elite Ten member?
I don't blame you for being surprised.
思いもよらねえだろうな
The only cooking techniques I taught Souma
were ones that'd be useful in a diner.
何しろ 創真には―
定食屋としての技術しか
仕込まなかったからな
Next to all the elites at this academy,
エリートぞろいの この学園じゃ
さぞかし浮いてるだろう
he must stick out like a sore thumb.
（一色）アハッ 確かに そうですね
You're certainly right about that.
But from the very first time
I faced off against Souma-kun,
でも 僕は創真君と
初めて勝負した時から―
I understood that he would
stir things up around here.
彼が この学園に波乱をもたらすと
確信していましたので
Really?
へえ～
Match
Well then, for the theme...
（城一郎）
さて 勝負のお題についてだが
Hey, Judge.
（城一郎）お～い 審査員の方
（創真）んっ？
What do you have a hankering for?
今 食いたい物は何だ？
Judge?
審査員？
（大御堂(だいみどう)ふみ緒(お)）
フフフッ 勝負好きは遺伝かい
似た者同士だねぇ まったく
I see that the competitive streak runs in the family.
The apple doesn't fall far from the tree, now does it?
Fumio-san?
ふみ緒さん
Jouichirou asked me last night
to oversee this match.
（ふみ緒）
ゆうべ 城一郎に頼まれてね
この勝負は あたしが取り仕切るよ
Well, this will be quite the spectacle.
いやあ これは見ものですね
（ふみ緒）ああっ ビックリした
Don't scare me like that!
Why are you even here, Isshiki?
一色！
なんで あんたがいるんだい？
アッハハッ
朝の畑仕事の帰りに―
I caught a whiff of an interesting match
on the way back from my morning fieldwork.
面白そうな勝負の匂いを
嗅ぎつけたもので
（ふみ緒）フンッ
残念だけど あんたは見学だよ
Unfortunately for you, you may only observe.
After all, we can't have an even number of judges.
審査員は奇数じゃないと
ああん？
Hm?
T-Tadokoro?
た… 田所？
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）うん？
Oh, Souma-kun.
あれ～ 創真君 おはよう
Morning.
Whoa, what happened?
うっ どうした？ それ
What's with the huge dark circles under your eyes?
目の下 クマがすげえぞ
Oh, those? Yeah, I'm really tired,
うん… 体は
すっごく疲れてるのに―
but whenever I try to fall asleep,
I end up thinking about camp.
合宿のこと思い出したら
眠れなくて
We need to finish fishing ASAP and get cooking!
急いで釣り上げて
調理に入らないと
うわわあ うわあっ！
（恵）あっ！
（男子生徒Ａ）どけよ 邪魔だ！
Watch where you're going!
What should I do? What should I do?!
どうしよう！　どうしよう！
I'm so sorry!
（恵）ごめんなさい
I'm kind of amazed that I survived all that.
“私 よく生き残れたなぁ”って
Well, it's all over now, so you should relax and get a good night's rest.
（創真）もう終わったんだから―
ゆっくり寝たほうが
いいんじゃねえか？
Oh, but this is perfect timing.
ああ でも ちょうどいい
恵も おいで
Come here, Megumi.
Huh?
はえ～？
With her here, we have three judges.
つまり これで審査員は３人
No objections, right?
構いませんね？
Yeah.
Yup.
うっす
You know, I'm no spring chicken.
でも まっ あたしも年だからねぇ
朝から重い物は受け付けない
I can't eat anything heavy in the morning,
and the girl pulled an all-nighter.
徹夜明けの子もいることだし
With that in mind, the theme should be...
そうだねぇ お題は―
Serve us a dish that'll give us a boost
and get us ready to start the day!
朝一の元気を出させる
一品を―
あたしらに作ってもらおう
You may use anything you can find in this kitchen.
食材は
この厨房(ちゅうぼう)内にある物なら自由
You have one hour.
制限時間は１時間
Now, begin!
それじゃあ 始め！
It has to be light and easy to eat,
重くなくて 食べやすくて
and yeah, it has to be nutritious of course.
そうだな　栄養も
しっかり取れるような…
よしっ！
Okay!
Huh?
うん？　ええっと…
Uh...
Why are they competing against each other?
えっ…
どうして ２人が勝負することに？
G'morning, Tadokoro-chan.
やあ 田所ちゃん
ようやく目が覚めたね
I guess you're finally awake.
Huh?
うんっ？ あれ？　なして なして？
What?
Why?
S-Souma-kun, your father was a member of the Elite Ten, right?
ん… 創真君
お父さんは元十傑なんでしょ？
How can you possibly win?
勝てっこないよ
Hey, it's not like this is
the first time we've done this.
（創真）いやあ でも 幸平家じゃ
これが日常なんだけどな
I think the first time I had a face-off with him was in sixth grade.
初挑戦は小６だったかな？
An elementary school student versus an adult?
小学生で大人相手に…？
I guess I can see Souma-kun doing that, but...
創真君らしいけど
あっ… まさか勝ったことも？
Hold on, have you ever beat him?
Oh, I can't really remember.
さあ どうだったっけかぁ？
Not even once.
ねえだろ　見栄張んな
Quit pretending.
I think you're on over 500 losses by now.
創真は だいたい
500敗くらい だったよな
Losses
No way! I've only lost 489 times!
違う！　489敗だ！
So you do remember.
しっかり覚えてんじゃねえか
A cooking match?
（ふみ緒）料理勝負だって？
Yes. And I'd like you to be the judge.
（城一郎）ああ　審査も任せたい
Well, I'll get to see you in a match for the first time in a very long while,
まっ 久しぶりに
あんたの勝負が見られるんだ
so I'm fine with adjudicating.
審査するのは
やぶさかじゃないけどね
But you'd better not take it easy on your opponent just because he's your son.
けど あんた―
実の息子相手だからって
手を抜いたりするんじゃないよ
You needn't worry about that.
そこは心配しなくていいぜ
When it comes to Souma,
I've never pulled any punches.
創真との勝負で手加減したことは
一度たりともねえからよ
Huh? An apple?
（恵）えっ？ リンゴ？
Souma-kun...
創真君 お父さんとはいえ―
He may be your father, but we're talking about the former second seat of the Elite Ten.
十傑第二席にいたほどの人と
戦ってるのに あんな堂々と…
So why do you look so confident?
I see.
（一色）なるほど
彼の原点は ここにあったのか
This is how he got started.
Souma-kun never backs down from a challenge,
創真君は乗り越える壁が
いかに強大でも 挑戦を厭(いと)わない
no matter how insurmountable it may seem.
And now I know why.
それもそのはずだ
He's been trying to surpass his father,
あまりにも実力のかけ離れた父に
彼は挑み続けてきたんだ
someone who far exceeds his own abilities,
0 Wins, 489 Losses
even after 489 losses.
489もの黒星を負いながら
Who'll be the first to finish?
先に仕上がるのは どっちだい？
Thank you for waiting!
お待ちどう！
That looks like...
それは？
An apple risotto.
（創真）リンゴのリゾットだ
Go on, have a taste!
さあ おあがりよ
A risotto?!
（ふみ緒）リゾットだって？
It's true!
（恵）本当だ
細かく角切りにしたリンゴが
I can see the finely diced apples.
Fruit in a risotto?
（ふみ緒）リゾットに果物とはねぇ
驚かせてくれるじゃないか
He sure likes surprising us, doesn't he?
A refreshing aroma that's both sweet and tart.
甘酸っぱくて 爽やかな香り
Did he also use lemons in this dish?
リンゴとレモンも入ってるのかな？
He did.
ああ すばらしい すがすがしさだね
The dish's fragrance is invigorating.
Just a whiff of it is enough to shake my leaden stomach awake and rouse my appetite.
この香りからして 重い胃を起こし
食欲を湧かせてくれる
It's enough to banish any fatigue.
眠気まで覚めるようだよ
An apple risotto, huh?
リンゴのリゾット
Well, why don't we see how it tastes?
では 肝心のお味は？
（３人）あむ
The apples lend a crisp texture
and a mellow sweetness.
（恵）
リンゴのシャキシャキとした食感と
優しい甘み
The simmered onions impart
a silky texture to the risotto.
トロッとするまで煮詰めた玉ネギ
Meanwhile, the crunchy bacon accents the gentle apple flavor that permeates the entire dish.
カリカリに焼いたベーコンを
アクセントに―
リゾット全体に
柔らかなリンゴの風味が広がってる
It's as though it's...
（恵）眠っていた体を…
gently waking me up from a long sleep.
（恵）ゆっくりと
起こしてくれてるみたい
Such a gentle kiss...
（恵）優しい口づけ
from the prince of apples!
リンゴの王子様だ
Apple...
（リンゴの王子）Apple(アップル)…
It's delicious!
おいしい～！
Now try seasoning it with black pepper.
（創真）お好みで
黒こしょうも どうぞ
It makes for a novel flavor that's just as good!
風味が変わって おいしいんだ
Let's see.
へえ～
The subtle sweetness of the apples and onions...
（ふみ緒）
リンゴや玉ネギの ほのかな甘み
...contrasts with the peppery
bite of the black pepper!
（一色）
黒こしょうの こうばしい刺激
The black specks on the white dish...
（ふみ緒）舞い落ちた黒こしょうが
この白い品に…
...create a contrast in both taste and appearance.
（一色）味覚と視覚の対比を
生み出している
It's like a waltz in black and white!
（ふみ緒･一色）
まるで黒と白のワルツ！
んんっ ハァ～ とろけちゃいそう
I think I'm going to melt!
It feels like it's sinking into my sleep-deprived body!
寝不足の体に
しみこんでくる感じです
You're getting vitamins, fats, and carbohydrates.
ビタミンに脂質
炭水化物も取れるし―
The rice is on the soft side,
so it's gentle on your stomach.
米は 柔らかめに仕上げてあるから
おなかにも優しい
It's perfect for eating right after you wake up.
まさに 起き抜けに
ぴったりの一品だ
But there's something I find puzzling.
しかし
これは どういうことだろう？
What is it?
何がですか？
The rice and onions have been infused with the flavor of apples,
（一色）米と玉ネギに しっかりと
リンゴの風味が移っているが―
but if the apples had been cooked that long,
そこまで煮込んだのなら
リンゴはグズグズに崩れているはず
they should've become mush.
Instead, they still have a crisp texture.
なのに なぜ
シャキッとした食感が？
You're right.
本当だ　一体 どうして？
How's that possible?
About that...
（創真）それはね
（恵）うん？
I used this!
こいつを使ったんだ
Apple juice?!
リンゴジュース？
While I was simmering the sauteed rice and onions,
（創真）炒めた米と玉ネギを
煮ていく時に―
I added the juice bit by bit as the dish was reduced.
このジュースを
少しずつ足しながら煮詰めたんだ
The diced apples were added later, and they were cooked just long enough to warm them.
角切りリンゴは そのあとに加えて
軽く火を通しただけ
That's why they retain their raw texture.
だから 食感は生きたままなんだよ
I see.
（一色）なるほど
すばらしい発想だ
What an innovative idea.
The flavor of apples permeates the dish,
全体に行き渡った
リンゴの一体感は―
and it was the apple juice that was behind it!
リンゴジュースで
作り上げたものだったとは
Even though he was presented with the theme right before he started,
（ふみ緒）
その場で出された お題に対して
ここまで的確な答えを出すなんて…
he was able to produce a dish
on the fly that was spot-on.
Is there any limit to his talent?
一体 どれだけの引き出しを
持っているんだい この子は
The apple risotto was an excellent
response to the assignment!
リンゴのリゾット
見事な回答だった
I can hardly imagine a better dish.
これ以上ないと思えるほどに
What a terrifying man.
（ふみ緒）
なんて恐ろしい男だろうねぇ
I can sense how he might be able to surpass
漂ってくる… 百点満点ともいえる
幸平創真のこの品を―
this near-perfect dish by Yukihira Souma with ease!
いともたやすく超えそうな気配が
Thank you for waiting.
（城一郎）お待ちどうさま
Now, please eat.
さあ 食べてくれ
Erina
the
Taster
Erina
the
Taster
Erina
the
Taster
Ack! I'm so sorry!
This is revolting!
It's as if 50,000 blue crabs had run rampant through idyllic farmland!
Absolutely horrid!
The dishes he prepared yesterday
（恵）昨日 作ってくれた料理
どれも すごい完成度だった
were all meticulous and polished.
What would he make for a contest?
勝負となったら 一体 どんな品が？
I'm honored to witness a dish made by a predecessor of the Elite Ten.
光栄ですね
十傑の大先輩の勝負料理が
拝めるとは
ハッ 城一郎は学生時代から―
During his time here, Jouichirou was well-known for his inventive dishes.
意外性のある攻めの料理に
定評があった
Take a long, hard look!
括目(かつもく)しな
Have a taste.
ご賞味あれ
It's Jouichirou's Special Rich Ramen.
城一郎特製 こってりラーメンだ
R...
ラ… ラーメン？
Ramen?!
Ramen for breakfast?!
（恵）あ… 朝からですか？
Wow. The broth looks really rich.
ああ… 濃そうなスープ
I've heard of places where ramen
is eaten in the morning,
（一色）
朝にラーメンを食べる地域も
確かにあるが―
but this appears to be made
with a thick seafood-based broth.
見たところ
魚介ドロドロスープ系のこってり感
This dish is too much for the sleep-deprived
Tadokoro-chan and the elderly Fumio-san.
寝不足の田所ちゃんと
お年を召した ふみ緒さんに―
この品は ちょっと…
Jouichirou!
（ふみ緒）城一郎！
意外性にも限度があるだろう！
Your obsession with novelty has gone too far!
I've warned you about this before!
まったく お前は昔っから そうだよ
Cooking Battle
You would serve up untested
recipes with bizarre ingredients
Cooking Battle
初めて試す新作やゲテモノ料理を
食戟(しょくげき)の場でも平気で出す
Cooking Battle
at a Cooking Battle without any hesitation!
And that's why you would lose
Cooking Battles from time to time!
そんなだから
なんてことない相手との食戟を―
ポロポロ落とすんだ
フッ あの頃の俺は
とがってたからなぁ
I was pretty ornery back then.
As if you've changed at all!
今も変わらんじゃないか！
んっ あれ？
Hm?
Fumio-san, the broth may look rich,
ふみ緒さん
これ 濃厚そうなスープだけど―
but it has a surprisingly light and mellow scent.
意外と くどくなくて
まろやかな香りです
んっ… 確かに
You're right.
Well anyway, let's see how this dish fares.
じゃあ とにかく審査だ
It's... not bad.
食べ… られる
Yuzu citrus was kneaded into these noodles.
この麺 ユズが練り込んである
Despite how rich the ramen is, I can keep eating.
こってりしてるのに
自然と箸が進んでいく
Or, rather, I...
（一色）…というより むしろ―
...I...
...just...
...can't stop!
The broth is a combination of
soy milk and scorched miso.
スープは豆乳と
焦がし味噌を合わせた物だ
But how would that alone be enough to produce such depth of flavor?
しかし それだけで
こんなにも深いコクが…
The ebi-imo taro I grated into the soy milk
and miso has an elastic texture and a rich taste.
味も濃くて きめ細かく
粘りがある えび芋を―
すりおろして加えてある
Doing so imparted a creamy depth to the broth.
そうすることで
クリーミーなコクが生まれるんだ
あっ なんだか
体がポカポカしてきたみたい
I feel like I'm being warmed from within.
It must be the effect of the chili oil,
grated ginger, and garlic.
ラー油と すりおろしのしょうが
ニンニクの効果だね
The mild soy milk masks
the bite of those ingredients,
豆乳の まろやかさによって
その刺激は和らげられ―
letting them gradually warm you up.
優しくジワジワと体を温めてくれる
A lot of work and attention to detail went into these toppings too.
そして トッピングも
細かな仕事のオンパレードだ
Lotus and burdock roots were thinly sliced and fried to a golden color.
薄切りのレンコンとゴボウは
カリッと色よく揚げ―
Carrots and turnips were grilled over charcoal until lightly scorched,
ニンジンと かぶらは―
炭火で軽く焦げ目がつくまで
焼き上げて―
then seasoned with rock salt to bring out their natural sweetness!
素材の甘みを引き出すように
岩塩で味付け
Just like in French cuisine,
フランス料理の付け合わせのように
１つ１つの材料に適した調理で―
each ingredient was prepared using a method uniquely suited to it,
in order to bring out its flavor.
味に奥行きを作っている
And to top it off, he used tempeh!
そして 極めつけが このテンペだ
Tempeh?
テンペ？
A fermented soy-based food product originating in Indonesia.
インドネシア発祥の
大豆を原料とする発酵食品
It's made by fermenting soybeans with tempeh mold,
大豆をハイビスカスや
バナナの葉に生息する―
which is found on hibiscus and banana leaves.
テンペ菌で発酵させるんだ
Tempeh is a traditional food that's been made for over 400 years.
現地では400年以上前から
親しまれている伝統食だよ
んっ うん あっさりしているのに
すごいボリューム感
It's light, but at the same time very filling.
It's almost like char siu pork!
チャーシューみたい
The texture of tempeh is close to that of meat,
食感が肉に似てるから
ベジタリアンやマクロビアン―
so it's often part of vegetarian and macrobiotic diets.
People who don't eat meat or dairy products can still enjoy tempeh.
肉や乳製品を取らない人も
好んで食べる物なんだ
For this dish, I prepared the tempeh by cooking it in soy sauce and sake.
今回は しょうゆと酒で
香ばしく照り焼きにしてみた
Could this be... a vegetarian broth?
もしかして これは… 精進だし！
That's right.
そのとおり
昆布とシイタケの合わせだし
It's made with kelp and shiitake mushrooms. No meat involved!
いわゆる 精進だしだ
When I was traveling overseas a long time ago,
昔 海外を旅してた時
宗教上のアレで―
I met a priest who was lamenting
数週間 肉や魚を
断たなきゃならないって―
that he had to abstain from meat and fish
for several weeks for religious reasons.
嘆いている坊さんと出会ってさぁ
I want to eat something filling!
（僧正）
もっと うまい物を食いたーい！
This ramen is based on what I learned through trial and error while making dishes for him.
その人に食わす品を
試行錯誤したことが―
このラーメンの土台に
なってるんだ
I see.
（ふみ緒）なるほど
The umami components of kelp and shiitake mushrooms have a synergistic effect when used in combination.
昆布とシイタケの
旨味成分は―
合わせて使うことで
相乗効果を発揮する
It makes it possible to attain a rich broth without using bonito fish.
かつお節などを使わなくても
しっかりとした旨味が…
Wait, Jouichirou!
待ちな　城一郎！
If that's the case, then this ramen...
…ということは このラーメン
肉も魚も一切 使わず―
You achieved this much complexity in flavor without using any meat or fish?
ここまでの深い味わいを
作り上げてるっていうのかい？
It's easy to use animal products to create umami and depth of flavor.
旨味やコクを出すには
動物性の物を使えば そりゃ簡単だ
But this is a rich ramen
that uses neither meat nor fish!
けど 肉も魚も使わない
こってりラーメン
Isn't that more interesting?
そっちのほうが 面白(おもしれ)えだろ？
What a guy!
（ふみ緒）なんてヤツだい
By combining the flavor of soy and other vegetables,
大豆や野菜のおいしさを
倍加させることで―
he created a dish that is deeply satisfying.
ここまで満足感のある品を
作り上げるとは
How many ideas are crammed into this single dish?
この１杯の中に どれだけの
アイデアが詰め込まれているのか
It contains the knowledge of a man
who's spent a lifetime traveling the world.
世界中を旅してきた男の
人生そのものが凝縮されている
Even though every bite leaves quite an impression,
（恵）インパクトたっぷりなのに
どんどん食べられちゃう
you never get overwhelmed!
What a pleasant, perfect spiciness!
（一色）
舌に心地よい 絶妙な辛さ
I can just feel the energy coursing through my veins!
エネルギーが巡っていくようだ
Ah, I feel so warm inside!
（ふみ緒）ああ… 体の内が熱い
My cells are rejuvenating!
細胞が若さを取り戻していく
（恵）戻る
Rejuvenating!
（一色）戻る
（ふみ緒）戻る～！
Tadokoro
Megumi
Thank you for the food!
Tadokoro
Megumi
（一色･恵）ごちとうたまでちた
Tadokoro
Megumi
（ふみ緒）ウホッ
The clock's been turned too far back!
戻りすぎだろ！
Let's get down to the judging!
それでは判定に入るよ
Thank God, I was just seeing things!
（創真）よかった 幻だった
But you do look somewhat younger.
あっ でも 若干 若返ってる
なんかツヤツヤしてる
In fact, you're kind of glowing.
Yukihira Souma or Jouichirou.
（ふみ緒）幸平創真と城一郎
Set forth the dish that was
more delicious in front of you!
より美味だったほうの食器を
前に出しな
It's unanimous.
満場一致
The victor is Jouichirou!
勝者 城一郎！
Glad you liked it!
御粗末！
Both demonstrated more than sufficient surprises,
（ふみ緒）
双方ともに意外性や驚き―
innovation, and consideration
of the diner in the morning.
そして 朝の体に配慮する
優しさは申し分なかった
But after tasting that ramen so full of vitality,
だが あの活力みなぎる
ラーメンを食べたあとだと―
Yukihira's dish feels lacking in comparison.
幸平の品は見劣りしてしまう
It's a complete victory for Jouichirou!
城一郎の完勝だ！
Souma-kun, your dish was certainly delicious,
（一色）創真君
（創真）うん？
（一色）君の料理も
とても おいしかった
but it seemed a bit lackluster to me.
でも 僕には少し
物足りないようにも感じたんだ
It is morning,
（一色）朝とはいえ
畑仕事を終えたところだからね
but I'd just finished fieldwork.
I guess I wanted something more substantial.
ガシッとした食べ応えのある
料理を求めてたんだ
Jouichirou-san's dish hit the spot.
城一郎さんの品は
それにピッタリだったよ
I see.
（創真）そうか
When I made that dish, all I thought about was
how to minimize discomfort and meet their needs.
俺の出した品は３人の欲求を
最低限 外さねえ物ではあった
Minimize
On the other hand, Dad aimed to maximize their enjoyment by fulfilling their desires.
でも 親父は３人 全員を―
最大限 満足させることまで
考えやがったのか
Maximize
But it's good to see you've grown up a little bit.
でも まっ
ちっとは成長してるんじゃねえか
Apple risotto, huh? Not bad.
リンゴのリゾット
なかなか面白い品だったぜ
Listen up, Souma.
（城一郎）いいか？　創真よ
While you're at Tohtsuki, you'll find
yourself with plenty of battles to fight.
遠月にいるかぎり
勝負はついて回る
Until the next time you lose to me,
次に俺に負けるまで
誰にも負けんじゃねえぜ
you'd better not lose to anyone else.
So they communicate through their cooking, huh?
語り合うのは料理でってわけかい？
What a pair those two make.
まったく よく似た親子だよ
But all that aside...
（城一郎）それはそれとして
（創真）あ？
Yeah?
This is your 490th loss, huh, Souma?
これで490敗目だなぁ？　創真
Hey!
ムッカーッ！
ヘッ 今回も勝利っと
Another win for me.
It's not as satisfying when I don't have a single defeat to my name.
黒星が１つもないってのも
味気ないもんだぜ
Shut up!
うるっせい！　次こそ見てやがれ
I'll show you next time!
Th-They're taking notes?!
きっ… 記録してる
Have they been recording every single win and loss since the beginning?
もしかして
今までの勝負を全部…？
They're oddly meticulous about things like that.
変に几帳面な所がある親子だねぇ
So you've been facing him over
and over again, Souma-kun.
（恵）創真君
ずっと
こうやって挑戦してきたんだ
You've been up against this amazing father
and experienced frustration many times over.
あんなにすごいお父さんに
ぶつかって―
何度も悔しい思いをして
Souma-kun, I'm going to keep trying too!
（恵）創真君！
（創真）えっ？
Huh?
（恵）私も頑張るね！
（創真）あっ？ おう…
Uh, okay.
（恵）うーん
さすがは創真君のお父さん
Your father's amazing.
I guess that's the power of the second seat!
あれが十傑第二席の実力なんだね
I guess.
そうだな　今までも
取る気 満々だったけどさ
It's not like my goal's changed, though.
I want to see what it's like up at the top,
where not even Dad's been.
（創真）親父でも見られなかった
てっぺんの景色
This has only made me even more fired up!
どんな眺めなのか 本気で
見てみたくなったって感じだな
Souma-kun...
創真君
All right!
よしっ！
田所も一緒に十傑 目指そうぜ！
Let's aim for the Elite Ten together, Tadokoro.
えっ ええっ！　私なんか無理だよ
Huh?
What?!
That's impossible for me!
いける いける
Don't be silly!
What, leaving already?
（ふみ緒）
やれやれ もう行くのかい？
せわしないことだよ
Do you ever relax?
You should give him some more advice.
もっとアドバイスでも
してやればいいのに
I'm pretty laissez-faire about parenting.
俺は放任主義なんでねぇ
He'll figure it out.
あとは自分で なんとかするだろう
Yeah, right.
よく言うよ
That match was meant to encourage him, wasn't it?
さっきの勝負だって
今後の激励のつもりだろ？
Since the Autumn Selection is coming up.
秋の選抜だってあるしね
Hm?
（城一郎）はて？
I just wanted to see my son's crestfallen face again.
俺は久しぶりに―
我が息子の悔しがる面(ツラ)を
見てえと思っただけだぜ
You could be more honest, you know.
素直じゃないねぇ
Well, I'll leave it at that.
まっ そういうことに
しといてやるよ
Besides, I had an errand to take care of at Tohtsuki.
それに 遠月に帰ってきたのは
ちょっとした用もあったからでさぁ
An errand?
（ふみ緒）用？
Oh, it's nothing important.
（城一郎）
いやぁ 大したことじゃねえんだ
Well, later, Fumio-san.
じゃあな ふみ緒さん
I'll come by sometime to cook for you.
また そのうち
飯作りにきてやるよ
My goodness.
（ふみ緒）
まったく… いい年こいても
風来坊は変わらないねぇ
No matter how old you get,
you'll never shake off your wanderlust.
My apologies, Erina-sama.
（新戸(あらと)緋沙子(ひさこ)）
申し訳ありません　えりな様
I'm sure you're tired from the training camp,
合宿翌日で お疲れと思いますが
本日 これからの予定です
but here is the schedule for today.
The owner and head chef of Kishoan will be arriving shortly to give you their regards.
まもなく 吉祥庵の
オーナーと料理長が―
あいさつにいらっしゃいます
They'd like you to taste their new menu.
新メニューを試食していただき
そのあとは―
Following that will be a group luncheon with Food Executive Company board members...
フードエグゼクティブ社
役員たちとの会食を
あっ 止めて！
Stop the car!
Erina-sama?
えりな様？　あの…
Ah, no, it's nothing.
（えりな）
いいえ 何でも… ありません
（吉野(よしの)悠姫(ゆうき)）ええ～っ？
What?!
Jouichirou-san already left?
城一郎さん もう行っちゃったの？
Wh-When did he leave?
い… いつですか？
Just now.
ついさっきだよ
どこ行くんだか知らないがね
I have no idea where he's off to, though.
（創真）まっ 自由すぎるだろ
He's too footloose.
He should've at least let us say goodbye.
見送りくらいさせろよな
あ～あ　城一郎さんに極星鶏の卵
食べてほしかったのになぁ
Aw, I wanted to let him try some eggs from my Polar Star chickens.
I wanted his advice.
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）
アドバイス もらいたかったわねぇ
朝のラーメンの お礼も
したかったのに
And I wanted to thank him for the breakfast ramen.
Ramen?
（悠姫･涼子）ラーメン？
Yeah...
うん　今朝 創真君と
城一郎さんが料理勝負を
Souma-kun and Jouichirou-san had a cooking face-off this morning.
What?!
何それ？　ずるい ずる～い！
How could you?!
私たちも呼んでよ～
You should've called us!
あああっ 堪忍な 堪忍な
Sorry! Please forgive me!
We're not going to forgive you!
（ふみ緒）そうだ 幸平
（創真）うん？
By the way, Yukihira.
Jouichirou had a message for you.
城一郎から あんたに伝言だよ
A message?
伝言？
Yeah.
ああ　“たまには店の風通しでも
しといてくれ”だとさ
"Air out the restaurant once in a while."
The restaurant?
店の？
（ふみ緒）今度の連休にでも
一度 帰ってみたらどうだい？
Why don't you go home for a bit
during the next holiday?
（創真）連休か…
Holiday, huh.
（富田(とみた)友哉(ゆうや)）
ハァ… どうなっちゃうんだろう？
この商店街は
I wonder what's going to happen
to this shopping district.
End
Next Episode
（緋沙子）次回「食戟のソーマ」
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
17品目の予定になっています
the seventeenth dish:
Menu
The Sensuous Karaage
The Sensuous Karaage.
「官能の唐揚げ」
It's only planned for now.
あくまで 予定です
Jouichirou
the
Wanderer
Jouichirou
the
Wanderer
Jouichirou
the
Wanderer
490 matches...
No wonder Souma's
grown so big now.
Crap. I haven't seen even
a single car come this way.